[theme music playing]
Hello, Raul. Come back here.
I have a surprise for you.
[Raul] What are you talking about, Emilia?
[tires screeching]
[crying] Jasmin!
-I'm here!
-[Emilia laughing]
Diego! Diego, help us, please!
My mother needs help!
Please! Please!
-I'll kill you!
-[Jepoy] I'm her bodyguard.
I won't let you hurt her.
[Ivy] To San Joaquin.
My mom will be safe there.
[Julio] You'll be running
for senator in my place.
You need Ivy's money
for our plans to push through.
[Diego] Are you Lily?
Are Ivy Aguas and Lily Cruz
the same person?
Yes, Diego. I'm your old friend.
-[Diego] Why did you lie to me?
-I have my reasons.
And even if I told you,
you wouldn't understand.
[Jepoy] There were no charred
remains in the building.
-Not one.
-That's impossible!
Don't stop until you can
show me a dead body.
[Ivy] Every time I see her suffering,
I remember the people who made her suffer.
Ivy, whatever your plans are,
I'll help you.
Because I love you.
[Ivy] You don't know what
you're saying, Diego.
-[Diego] Mrs. Camia…
-[Camia] Raul, you bastard!
If it weren't for you,
I wouldn't be like this!
Get away from me!
[Diego] Ivy, is it true
my dad's the reason
your mother's this way now?
Yes! My mother is like that
because of Raul!
Because of your good-for-nothing father!
[tense music playing]
[tires screeching]
[gasps]
Don't step out of the car
no matter what happens, okay?
Good grief. Why can't we leave the house
without being bothered by the Ardientes?
Stay alert.
[uneasily] Uh… What's this about, Mayor?
[Arnaldo] I talked to Miss Aguas
on the phone,
and I know she's on vacation.
I need to know exactly where she is.
With all due respect, Mayor,
she wants to have some time alone.
That's the thing. She's alone.
And Ivy is a woman.
She needs someone to protect her.
Oh, Ivy doesn't need a man to protect her.
She can defend herself.
Besides, she's with…
With whom, Carlotta?
Tell me, who is with Miss Aguas?
[suspenseful music playing]
[Ivy] That's the truth!
For 13 years, he kept my mother hidden.
Ivy, wait. I don't understand.
Why would my dad do that to your mother?
You want answers
but can't connect the dots?
Well, I don't understand either, Diego!
When we were kids,
your father tried to rape my mother.
Did you forget about that, Diego?!
Okay, let me remind you.
I'll tell you everything!
My family moved to Poblacion Ardiente…
because we thought our lives
would be better there.
[Julio] Viva Ardiente!
-[all] Viva Ardiente!
-Viva Ardiente!
[all] Viva Ardiente!
[Ivy] Little did we know…
the leaders of that town were all evil!
Then, one day Raul tried
to rape my mother.
-[Lily] Mom.
-Dad.
You bastard!
-[Lily] Dad! Dad!
-[Diego] Dad! Dad! Dad!
-[Dante groaning]
-Dad!
-[Camia] Leave us alone!
-[Lily] Stop it!
I'll file a case against you.
[Ivy] Yes, Diego.
That's when it all started.
That's how my family met its ruin.
All because of your father.
When my father learned about it,
he tried to seek justice.
But after he spoke to Emilia,
what happened to him?
He died. Or should I say…
he was killed!
You killed my husband!
You murderers! Get out of here!
[Ivy] Would you believe…
he died of a heart attack?
After my father died,
did you know what they did to my mother?
She was raped and tortured!
-[shushes]
-[Tonio] Hey!
Lily… Run!
So, for 13 years, I thought
both my parents were dead!
I thought I was all alone!
So, once more…
Your worthless father raped my mother!
And your mother had
both my parents killed!
Even me, Diego!
She tried to have me killed!
You heard me right, Diego.
She wanted me dead!
[young Lily crying] No! Please don't!
Your grandfather, your mother,
and your father,
the people who rule Poblacion Ardiente,
they had us slaughtered
like we were animals.
All of them, Diego.
[tense music playing]
Lily, I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I tried to find you.
Believe me, Lily. I looked for you.
And if I'd found you,
you wouldn't have suffered alone.
You can't do anything about it,
Diego. The damage has been done.
Is that why you came back here?
To get back at my family?
Ivy, seeking revenge won't solve anything.
It'll only be harder on you.
Just leave.
-Ivy, listen to me--
-I said get out!
I want you to go. Get out!
I said out!
Ivy, I'm sorry.
[dramatic music playing]
[sighs]
[sobbing]
I knew it.
Diego is with Miss Aguas.
Those two traitors.
I can smell them
from miles away. They stink!
Don't worry, Grandpa.
We'll make Diego tell us
where he's hiding Ivy.
And I'm sure the people from the
co-op know where my brother is.
If we need to burn that place
and tear down the houses,
including those beggars
living there, then do it.
If that's what it takes for us
to know where those two are.
[Julio sighs]
[Jepoy] Mr. Fred.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Jepoy] Ivy, Emilia doesn't know anything.
Even though we're apart and
Emilia's keeping an eye on me,
no Ardiente will lay a finger on you.
I'm still yours, Ivy.
Mister Fred.
-I'll leave it to you.
-Okay. Thank you.
-Just do the usual.
-Okay.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Loring] We really don't know
where Diego is.
He hasn't come home in a few days.
Why are you looking for him?
I'm sure that he's with Miss Aguas.
Or…
I could be wrong.
Maybe you're the one
hiding that two-faced woman.
-No, we're not.
-We're not hiding her.
[chuckles]
But aren't you on her side now
because she bought you land?
That obviously means you work for her now.
That also means you love her now.
-It's not like that.
-[Julio] No.
-It's just…
-We're not…
[shushes]
There's no need to explain.
I'm still your Señor Julio.
And my prodigal children
need to be punished.
If you don't tell me
where Miss Ivy Aguas is…
you'll see what I'm capable of.
Congressman, we really don't
know anything about this.
[Loring] We don't know.
-We don't know where she is!
-We don't know.
[Fernan] We aren't hiding her.
[tense music playing]
[tires screeching]
[screams]
[young Lily crying] Why did Mom
say… they killed Dad?
-[young Diego] I didn't know.
-He's dead!
[Loring] Come on. Come on. Sorry, Lily.
[young Diego wailing]
[young Diego]
They said a crime took place.
Daddy, you know a lot of cops, right?
-Let's find Lily.
-You know, Diego…
It's better if
you don't expect to ever see Lily again.
-[Julio] You idiot!
-What did I do, Grandpa?
You caused a huge scandal!
Because of you,
people are talking about a child
who's gone missing
from Poblacion Ardiente!
[tense music playing]
[Diego] My whole life, I thought
my family could still change.
But if they don't,
I'll turn my back on them.
I'll help you get justice, Ivy.
[tense music playing]
[Claire] Raul.
[sighs] Drunk again.
Look at this mess. Good grief.
Ma'am, for Mr. Raul.
-What's this?
-A letter.
Thank you.
[Emilia] Aunt Claire, what's that?
[suspenseful music playing]
A summons for Raul.
Someone filed a report against him.
[Dr. Faustino] Try to color
within the lines.
Can you do that, Camia?
[slow instrumental playing]
Mom.
Ivy.
I'm glad you still remember my name.
Uh… I'll leave you here with Ivy, then.
Okay, Doc.
Ivy?
You look sad.
Where is Diego?
Did you two have a fight?
Diego had somewhere to be.
Where did he go?
Don't worry about that, Mom.
You have to focus on your rehab.
Hopefully, you'll get better soon.
You'll get better, right?
Yes, Ivy.
For you, I will.
[slow instrumental playing]
-Sir, where are you going?
-I want to talk to Dad.
Mr. Raul's not here.
Dad! Dad!
Diego. Seems like you're
barking up the wrong house.
[chuckles]
I went to the co-op.
It's been a few days
since they last saw you.
Where did you go?
I had something to take care of, Grandpa.
Well…
I need details.
[stutters] Co-op business.
[chuckles]
Come on, Diego. Don't lie to me.
You were with Ivy Aguas, weren't you?
[suspenseful sting]
Who told you that?
I don't even know where Ivy is.
Perhaps…
you'll tell me the truth if I told you…
that the lives of your friends
at the cooperative…
depend on it.
Grandpa, I'm begging you.
Leave the farmers out of this.
-I don't know where Ivy is!
-[chuckles]
I will ask you one last time.
Where is Ivy Aguas?
[tense music playing]
I don't know where she is, Grandpa.
Oh, well.
Very well, then.
[tense music playing]
[Diego] Nanny?
Hey.
Nanny, I know Grandpa
came here to threaten you.
I'm sorry for dragging you into this mess.
Your grandpa's insane.
He told us you know
where Miss Aguas really is.
I just find it ridiculous.
[bleak music playing]
Diego, what's wrong?
Is there something we should know?
Nanny, I'm sorry.
But I can't answer that question.
What kind of answer is that, Diego?
Well, then remember this.
No matter what happens, we'll
always be here for you, okay?
Nanny, thank you.
Aunt Claire.
You have to help me get out of here.
[Claire] Where are you going?
[Emilia sighs] I need to find out
who filed the police report against Raul.
-[Claire] But why?
-Because I have to protect him.
Emilia, you'd disobey your
father again just for that man?
Oh, Emilia, when will you ever learn?
[sighs] I'll take care of it.
Leave it to your Aunt Clarita.
[man] You're not allowed to leave, sir.
Even there? Please?
Do you know who Camia is?
Can't you understand
what I feel right now?
Or not?
You don't know her, right?
-That's why you guys--
-[bottle shatters]
That's why you guys can do this to me!
[panting]
[crying] You know nothing…
You know nothing at all.
You don't know how it hurts me.
[sobbing] Camia…
[tense music playing]
-[Camia] There's a fire!
-[Ivy] Mom…
[Camia coughs] Fire!
[Camia] Fire!
[Camia and Ivy gasping]
[Ivy coughs]
[Camia coughing]
[suspenseful music playing]
-[panting] Fire!
-Mom! Mom?
-Mom.
-Fire! Fire!
-Mom, there's no fire.
-Fire!
-Fire! Fire!
-Mom, there's no fire. Nurse!
-Nurse!
-Fire…
-Mom, there's no fire.
-Fire!
Mom, sit down. Mom. Mom. You're safe here.
Shh… Nurse.
-There's a fire.
-Mom.
[Camia panting]
Shh… Mom, you're safe here.
You're safe, Mom.
[dramatic music playing]
Doc, isn't there any way
to speed up my mom's recovery?
As I see it, she's only getting worse!
Miss Aguas, I have to remind you
that this is not going to be easy.
I'm really sorry, but she has
far too many painful memories,
which were trapped in her mind
for 13 years.
It's very hard for her.
So, what do you mean?
That there's no chance
my mom will ever recover?
Doc, tell me the truth.
I need to know the truth!
Is this a hopeless case?
I have to be honest with you, Miss Aguas.
Only a miracle can cure her now.
[ominous music playing]
Madrigal, no one must ever know
what you might hear tonight.
Especially Julio.
Yes, ma'am.
Let him off, Auntie.
Madrigal is loyal to me.
Where is that woman?
-Belen? Belen, right?
-Yes.
I am Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
Former governor of Poblacion Ardiente.
Just to let you know,
I care for the masses.
I don't want them taken advantage of,
so even if Raul is my husband…
if he's done something wrong…
he must be punished.
What did Raul do?
Why did you file a complaint?
He kidnapped Jasmin and hid her.
"Jasmin"?
[Dr. Faustino]
But there's another treatment
that we haven't done yet.
It's called the ECT.
ECT? Electroconvulsive therapy?
You'll induce a brain seizure
in my mother?
Doc, isn't that dangerous?
No, it's considered safe.
But usually, it's the
last resort for cases like this.
How will that affect my mother?
Well, yet again I need to be
honest with you, Miss Aguas.
There are risks involved
in using this treatment.
She might suffer permanent memory loss.
Or her condition could become much worse.
But there is also a possibility
that she'll get better.
Are you saying that
I'd be risking my mother's
mental health on a procedure
that has no guarantee of success?
Is that it?
[exhales]
[Belen] Raul brought her to me
to take care of her.
That was 13 years ago.
She had a gunshot wound
and wasn't herself.
But when she started to get better,
Raul suddenly changed.
He kept Jasmin locked up.
He wouldn't let her out.
Not even to see a doctor.
And one time,
I tried helping Jasmin escape,
but Raul hurt me too.
[tense music playing]
Do you know what Jasmin's full name is?
No, ma'am.
But there was a woman I spoke to
who called Jasmin by another name.
She called her…
Camia.
[dramatic music playing]
[Belen] She was beautiful,
tall, and fair-skinned.
You might've seen her.
Please help me find her.
Camia?
[tense music playing]
-[Emilia] Raul.
-[Raul] What?
Where are you hiding her?
Did you let her escape again? Answer me!
What are you talking about?
I'm not hiding anything
or anyone! She's dead!
I could kill you right now, you liar!
Why do you want to kill me?
Camia's gone, she's dead!
Isn't that what you want to hear?
Thirteen years, Raul.
You made me believe that you changed.
Until I found out you had another secret!
Why are you so obsessed with her?
Because I love Camia.
And the truth is, you'll never understand
how much I love her.
[dramatic music playing]
[sobbing]
-Are you done?
-I loved you, Raul.
I still love you.
I gave you everything. Everything!
Until I had nothing left for myself!
This is the thanks I get?
Kill me now!
-Kill me now! Just kill me now!
-Make her stop.
[Emilia weeping]
That's enough. Let's go. Emilia.
[bleak music playing]
[tense music playing]
Mom, I spoke to your doctor.
She told me there's something
we haven't tried yet.
A procedure.
[sighs] But then…
There's no guarantee
the procedure will work.
I don't want to risk your mental health.
I don't want your memories to disappear.
[sighs heavily]
Ivy. Are you crying?
Why?
Don't be sad.
Take this so you'll feel better.
Don't be afraid, okay?
Don't be sad.
Fight.
Hope. Change.
That's what I learned from my husband.
Mom?
Mom.
[bleak music playing]
What is it, Diego? Why are you here?
Do you want to judge me too?
Go and judge me all you want!
Say what you want to say!
Tell me all of my mistakes!
Well?
Why did you do it?
What?
What did I do? What do you mean?
Why did you do that to Mrs. Camia?
Why did you take advantage of her?
Why did you cage her like an animal?
Why didn't you take her to a doctor?
I thought you loved her!
-Yes, I love Camia!
-Do you?
What kind of love is that?
Tell me the truth.
Why did you do that?
Why did you do that, Dad?!
Diego, listen to me. Yes, I admit.
I'm the reason
why her family's all dead now.
Emilia massacred her family.
But they were wrong. Camia survived!
When I found her, I saved her!
I saved her!
I hid her from Emilia
because I love Camia!
[sighs] Doc, I don't understand.
I can talk to her like my mother.
Maybe there's a chance she'll get better.
Maybe she doesn't need to undergo ECT.
But that is not a clear indication
that she's feeling better.
Sometimes, patients with
temporary memory loss
experience having false memories,
invented memories,
real memories misplaced in time.
[exhales]
So, she still needs to undergo an ECT?
In other cases,
the family accepts the patient's condition
and they just improve the
quality of life of the patient.
But in your case,
if you want to fight it out,
we've yet to try
electroconvulsive therapy.
[sighs]
Please consider this,
Miss Aguas. For your mother.
-Thank you. You may go now.
-Okay.
[tense music playing]
[exhales]
We have a pressing matter, Auntie.
I need to find that Camia.
I don't understand.
All this trouble to find Raul's mistress?
Because I'm the one who had her killed…
she can ruin our family's name.
I need to bury her back
in the grave she crawled out of!
[ominous music playing]
Are they fighting again?
Or just watching a soap opera?
[Arnaldo sighs]
Well, I can sense that you want
to tell me what the problem is.
Come on. Spit it out, grandson.
Camia Cruz…
a woman Mom killed a long time ago.
She's still alive.
[suspenseful sting]
What you did was wrong.
My whole life, Dad.
My whole life, you made me
believe you were a good man.
But it was all you.
If you hadn't gone after Mrs. Camia,
this wouldn't have happened to Lily.
She was my best friend.
You did this to my best friend!
How could you do this?!
Diego, I made a mistake.
Yes, you did.
If it weren't for your womanizing,
none of this would've happened
to Lily or our family!
What family? Huh?
You and I are the only family here, Diego.
Just the two of us. Do you understand?
-What are you talking about?
-Listen.
Dad, stop it! Don't drag me
into this family's mess!
Diego…
You aren't related to the Ardientes.
Not to Emilia, or Julio…
Emilia's not your real mother.
[suspenseful sting]
Diego.
I'm sorry.
[young Diego crying] Ouch!
[Julio] Feel the pain!
You have to become a real Ardiente!
I really don't understand
how you can be an Ardiente.
You're the only disgrace to this family.
[young Arnaldo] You don't act
like an Ardiente.
There's no weak Ardiente.
So that's why.
That's why they treat me like this.
And you, Dad…
You hid it from me?
Why?
Son, I'm on your side.
Son, I'm here… Son… Son, listen--
All my life, I believed in you.
-I know I'm not perfect…
-What kind of father are you?
I've never been a perfect dad,
but I'll never leave you.
-I'll fix this.
-Dad, stop it. Stop.
[panting]
You're a worthless father.
You're just like them.
-You are just like them!
-It's just you and me…
Diego… Diego! Diego!
Son! Son!
Diego!
[panting]
[sobbing]
[melancholic music playing]
-Ma'am, the guards are gone.
-Okay, good.
[dramatic music]
Madrigal.
Stay where you are.
Emilia.
You told me to trust you.
You promised you would change.
Killing is the only thing you know,
and yet, you still fail.
[Julio scoffs]
How is Camia Cruz still alive?
-I will fix this problem, Papa.
-What? You?
I'm sure you'll fail again.
I don't want you
to have anything to do
with catching that woman.
But I will.
I will fix this problem.
[Julio] Go!
Wait, what are you doing?
Wait, Papa! Papa! Please!
-[door closes]
-Papa! Papa!
Don't lock me up in here!
[pounding on door]
Papa! Open the door!
[Emilia pounds on door]
Papa!
[dramatic music playing]
[exhales]
Hmph!
Arnaldo?
-Arnaldo.
-[door closes]
You have to get me out of here.
Please help me, son. I need to find Camia.
I mean, this is all my fault,
so let me pay for this.
No. You will do nothing, okay?
Grandpa already ordered us
to look for Camia.
But, Arnaldo, I feel so useless.
Son, look at me.
I'm the former governor of Ardiente.
And now, I'm locked here.
I'm locked here! I'm locked here!
You can't look for her, okay?
First of all, you have no machinery.
And I can't provide you with that
because Grandpa will find out.
Then let me make my
own machinery, my own empire.
-How will you do that?
-Take me to Ivy Aguas.
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] Jepoy, thank you
for bringing these over.
I'm sure this will help Mom.
How's she doing?
She's still sick.
Jepoy, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
[sighs]
Ivy. We need to keep
a closer eye on your mom.
Emilia knows she was
in that burned-down house.
And she suspects she's still alive.
Does she?
Then I need to be ready in case
Emilia figures us out.
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
-Okay, thank you.
-Well?
There's a certain rest house in Bataan
that doesn't accept guests,
and it's owned by Aguas Realty.
Then…
You know, son, we should go now.
Let's go there.
Mom, this is the only time
I'm going to do this.
I know, son. I'm really thankful to you.
Just you?
I was expecting more of you here.
-Where are the others?
-They're on their way, ma'am.
Okay. This is what you'll do.
I want all of you to guard every
nook and cranny of this resort.
-Do you understand?
-Yes, ma'am. As you wish.
That'll be all.
[bodyguard] Check upstairs.
[slow instrumental playing]
[Camia crying, banging on door]
[door opens]
Mom?
What's wrong, Mom? Mom.
What's happening to you?
[panting]
Don't you like it here?
I'll move you to another room,
or we can leave if you want.
[Raul] It'd be for the best
if we go away for now.
We're moving away from here.
[Camia screaming]
-Leave?
-Yes.
No. I want to stay. I don't want to leave.
-Are you sure?
-I don't want to.
Don't make me leave. I wanna stay.
-I wanna stay.
-Okay, Mom.
I'm staying here. I'm not leaving!
-I don't want to leave!
-Okay, Mom. We won't.
We won't leave.
-I don't want to leave.
-We're not leaving.
You can stay here, Mom. Calm down.
[tense music playing]
Mom, sit down.
Ivy.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right, Mom.
You don't have to apologize.
I'll leave you for a moment.
Uh…
What are those?
Books and other stuff.
They might help jog your memories, Mom.
But you can take a look
at these once you've rested.
Oh, no.
I want to see them.
All right.
[slow instrumental playing]
Mom, these books…
they're what you used
when you were still teaching.
And this.
This notebook…
Dad wrote…
365 Days of Love and Guidance…
as a guide for me when I grow up.
[somber music playing]
This is you, Mom.
This is Dad.
And this is… Lily.
Dante?
Lily.
Lily, my daughter. My daughter, Lily.
[Emilia] Hi. Good morning.
-Is Miss Aguas here?
-I'm sorry.
We aren't accepting
any visitors at the moment.
-We aren't your typical guests.
-[Diego] They killed my mother!
Where's the justice?
-The Ardientes will kill you…
-[Loring] Pandoy!
…if you go against them!
[Emilia] I need a huge sum of money
to get back into power and stop
my enemies' plans against me.
Like this one person.
I don't know if you're
familiar with her. Camia Cruz?
-[Camia] Ouch! Stop it!
-[glass shattering]
[Emilia] What's that sound?
[Arnaldo] Why are there nurses here?
[theme music playing]